Guide to the Ali Akbar Bushiri Collection AD.MC.039
NYU Abu Dhabi, Archives and Special Collections
- Safar and Sharif families, 1839-1977; Bulk, 1895-1950
  - Sharif, Mohammed Khalil:, 1896-1940
    - Miscellaneous, English, 1905-1931, and undated (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Pension, 1929-1939 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Property and residences, Basra, 1906-1915 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Property and residences, Bushire, 1909-1926 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Sharif, Mohsen Mohammed (Shiraz, brother of Mohammed Khalil), 1898-1937 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Sharif, Mohammed Taher
    - Bahrain Petroleum Company (BAPCO), 1939-1948 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Business and financial: general, 1925-1957 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Business and financial: laundry, 1950-1962 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence: Ahmed, Mohammed (attorney), 1928-1961 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence: Belgrave, Charles, and family, 1939-1949, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence: British Residency, Bahrain--social, 1948-1965 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence: General, incoming, 1929-1955 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence: General, outgoing, 1928-1959, and undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence: Kanoo, Yusuf, circa 1919-1956 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence: Khalifa, Mohammed bin Issa, 1948-1949 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Gray Mackenzie and Co.: general, 1943 and undated (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Gray Mackenzie and Co.: labor contracting, 1936-1944 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Gray Mackenzie and Co.: provisioning of ships, annual contracts, 1930-1942 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Gray Mackenzie and Co.: provisioning of ships, individual vessels, 1939-1942 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Miscellaneous, 1926-1950, and undated (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Political Agency, Bahrain, 1939-1955 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Property, 1947 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Sharif family: miscellaneous, 1924 and undated (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Sharif family: property, Bahrain, 1947-1957 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Sharif family: property, general, circa 1923-1926 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Sharif family: research about, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Unidentified documents (photocopies), 1838-1939, and undated (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Unidentified documents (originals), circa 1905-1912, and undated (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Unidentified property documents (original), 1906-1913 (Box 8, Folder 24)
- Unidentified materials: unsorted
  - Unidentified /unsorted photocopies (Box 9)
  - Unidentified/unsorted photocopies (Box 10)
  - Unidentified/unsorted photocopies (Box 11)
  - Unidentified/unsorted photocopies (Box 12)
- Ledgers and oversize materials
  - Oversize documents
    - Bushiri, Ali Kazem: documents (inheritance and unidentified), circa 1909-1917 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Bushiri, Hussein Ali Kazem: Iran, Ministry of Justice, circa 1954-1955 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Bushiri, Hussein Ali Kazem: property and inheritance, undated, circa 1940s-1950s (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Bushiri family: Business, miscellaneous, undated, Unidentified dates (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Safar family: property and inheritance documents, circa 1883-1905 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Safar family: deed of sale of property [Abdul Rasul bin Mohammed Ali Safar?], circa 1879 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Safar, Mohammed Rahim: document related to his estate (?), circa 1914 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous: Bahrain, Government of: Nationality Law, 1937 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous: Port William Port Clearance document, with inventory of ship's cargo bound for Bombay, 25 April, 1833 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous: Poster of world leaders, Persian text with photographs, 1938 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous: [fragile documents in need of conservation treatment/restoration] (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Bushiri family ledger books: annual
    - Annual ledger, 1937 (Box 14, Volume 1)
    - Annual ledger, 1941-1948 (Box 14, Volume 2)
    - Annual ledger, 1939 (Box 15, Volume 1)
    - Annual ledger, 1940 (Box 15, Volume 2)
    - Annual ledger, 1949-1952 (Box 15, Volume 3)
  - Bushiri family ledger books: daily
    - Daily ledger, 1929-1931 (Box 16, Volume 1)
    - Daily ledger, 1938-1940 (Box 16, Volume 2)
    - Daily ledger, 1941 (Box 17, Volume 1)
    - Daily ledger, 1945-1946 (Box 17, Volume 2)
    - Daily ledger, 1948 (Box 18, Volume 1)
    - Daily ledger, 1949-1950 (Box 18, Volume 2)
    - Daily ledger, 1950 (Box 18, Volume 3)
    - Daily ledger, 1951 (Box 18, Volume 4)
  - Dheramdas, Ioverohangos: business ledgers
    - Ledger, 1944-1955 (Box 19, Volume 1)
    - Ledger, 1944-1955 (Box 18, Volume 2)
    - Ledger, 1944-1955 (Box 18, Volume 3)
    - Ledger, 1944-1955 (Box 18, Volume 4)
    - Ledger, 1944-1955 (Box 18, Volume 5)
    - Ledger, 1944-1955 (Box 18, Volume 6)
    - Ledger, unknown dates (Box 18, Volume 7)
    - Ledger, unknown dates (Box 18, Volume 8)
    - Ledger, 1955-1956 (Box 19, Volume 1)
    - Ledger, 1956 (Box 19, Volume 2)
    - Ledger, 1956-1957 (Box 19, Volume 3)
    - Ledger, 1957-1958 (Box 20, Volume 1)
    - Ledger, 1958-1959 (Box 20, Volume 2)
    - Ledger, unknown dates (Box 21, Volume 1)
    - Ledger, unknown dates (Box 21, Volume 2)
    - Ledger, unknown dates (Box 22, Volume 1)
    - Ledger, unknown dates (Box 22, Volume 2)
    - Ledger, unknown dates (Box 23, Volume 1)
    - Ledger, unknown dates (Box 23, Volume 2)
    - Ledger, unknown dates (Box 24, Volume 1)
    - Ledger, unknown dates (Box 24, Volume 2)
    - Ledger, unknown dates (Box 25, Volume 1)
    - Ledger, unknown dates (Box 25, Volume 2)
    - Ledger, unknown dates (Box 25, Volume 3)
    - Ledger, unknown dates (Box 25, Volume 4)
    - Ledger, unknown dates (Box 25, Volume 5)
    - Ledger, unknown dates (Box 26, Volume 1)
    - Ledger, unknown dates (Box 26, Volume 2)
    - Ledger, unknown date (Box 26, Volume 3)
    - Ledger, 1951? (Box 27, Volume 1)
    - Ledger, 1952? (Box 27, Volume 2)
    - Ledger, 1954? (Box 27, Volume 3)
    - Ledger, 1954? (Box 27, Volume 4)
    - Ledger, 1954? (Box 27, Volume 5)
    - Ledger, 1955? (Box 27, Volume 6)
    - Ledger, Unknown (Box 27, Volume 7)
    - Ledger, Unknown (Box 27, Volume 8)
  - Manama, port of: Shipping records, circa 1951-1958
    - Ledger, ca. 1951-1958 (Box 29, Volume 1)
    - Ledger, circa 1951-1958 [?] (Box 30)
    - Ledger, 1951-1958 [?] (Box 31)
    - Ledger, Circa 1951-1958 (Box 32)
  - Manuscript: Mallallah Mohammad Karim Husain Ajmi (Box 33)
  - Matam al 'Ajam al Kabeer: ledger book
    - Ledger book, 1353 A.H.? (Box 28, Volume 1)
  - Sharif, Mohammed Taher al-: copy books, 1936, and 1349-1354 A.H. [?]
    - Copy book 1 (Box 34, Volume 1)
    - Copy book 2 (Box 34, Volume 2)
    - Copy book 3 (Box 34, Volume 3)
- Matam al 'Ajam: Qur'an segments
  - Juz Qalal Malao 9, Surah Al Aaraf and Al Anfal, 12 Ramadhan 1286 AH (Box 35, Folder 1)
- Photographs